# JOE JORDAN

Full-stack web developer with strong creative problem-solving skills and attention to detail. Years of experience as a teacher and set builder translates to ability to work with designers and teams, meet deadlines, and deliver a usable, high-quality product.

#### TOOLS & SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Node.js, Express, MongoDB
- React, Angular
- React Native
- Jest, Cucumber, Puppeteer
- Responsive design
- Writing/editing/research
- Trained in communication

## STRENGTHS

- Diligent and personable
- Creative problem-solver
- Expertise in hearing and addressing client concerns
- Committed to promoting a safe and enjoyable work environment

# EDUCATION

2022 • CareerFoundry Full-Stack Immersion Program

Intensive, mentored, project-based online training program in contemporary full-stack web development

2014 • Texas Region 10 ESC Teacher Certification, ELAR 8-12

Nationally recognized certification program for post-graduate teacher training

1994 • UC Santa Barbara Bachelor of Arts, English

Comprehensive liberal arts education with a focus on English literature

lankyjoe.com

github.com/shplank

in linkedin.com/in/lankyjoe

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Theater Operations Specialist**

CSU Dominguez Hills | Carson, CA | 2019-present

- Streamlining operational flow by proactively interfacing with faculty, staff, and outside clients to schedule and facilitate events and productions
- Paving the way for increasingly intricate theatrical designs based on flawless execution of designer plans
- Decreasing build times and inefficiency by training dozens of student workers in high-end carpentry skills and safe building protocols
- Improving organization and maintenance procedures for large, busy shop facility and theater space

## **Technical Director**

Sacred Fools Theater Company | Los Angeles, CA | 2017-18

- Boosted clientelle base and reputation by establishing positive, supportive customer experiences
- Reorganized technical spaces to create more userfriendly environment for clients and in-house technicians
- Bolstered facility's staff by 60% through competency training in a variety of technical theater skills
- Attracted high-caliber designers and technicians by working closely with them to execute designs to the highest standards of safety and artistry

#### **English Teacher**

Bonham High School | Bonham, TX | 2014-17

- Raised the bar for rigorous, standards-based instruction in a chronically underserved community
- Improved students' standardized test scores by 12% on average as well as overall passing and graduation rates
- Elevated school's profile by coaching academic teams to unprecedented regional competition victories
- Fostered more inclusive learning environment for all students, including promoting and advising school's first Gay-Straight Alliance program

References available upon request.